+64 27 302 1676 colls.lauren@gmail.com www.laurencolls.com

LAUREN COLLS

O in Web Developer

ABOUT ME

I discovered a capacity and enthusiasm for programming while developing a slot machine application as part of my MSc research. The purpose of the app was to study the behavioural effects of different slot machine features.

On completion of my degree I studied web development at Enspiral Dev Academy. Here I was trained as a full-stack JavaScript developer and gained experience developing with Node.js, and a constantly expanding list of modern frameworks.

I am now focused on continuous learning in this field and on finding a role in the web development industry.

I enjoy the excitement of coming up with creative solutions for complex problems.

EDUCATION

Master of Science with Distinction

Behavioural Psychology Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand April 2015 - April 2016

I investigated the effect of near win outcomes on slot machine gambling behaviour. For this I developed a simulated slot machine application using Visual Basic in Visual Studio.

Bachelor of Science with Honours

Psvchology

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand March 2010 - November 2014

A classroom and thesis based programme, for which I used eyetracking technology to study the conditions in which human observing behaviour can be disrupted.

KEY COMPETENTCIES

Node.js Tape

JavaScript (ES5/ES6) Visual Basic **JQuery Express** HTML React.is CSS **OAuth** Git SQL Sublime Text Linux Github Windows NPM OSX

Visual Studio

Heroku

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Web Developer in training

Enspiral Dev Academy (EDA), Wellington

February 2016 - July 2016

A web development programme that provided intensive and practical programming experience that focused on:

- full-stack JavaScript (Node.js, ES5/6, Express, React.is, Redux)
- object orientated programming
 pair programming
- functional programming
- MVC architecture
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass
- SQL and noSQL databases
- unit/integration testing
- TDD
- engineering empathy
- · agile development

Freelance Web Developer

Wellington

December 2015 - June 2016

I have been involved in the development of a videographer's portfolio (www.bryson-rooney.com), and a small business site. Both projects required clear communication and understanding of the clients' needs. These projects are ongoing.

PROJECTS

Eatr - Restaurant finding application with a tinder-like interface.

Based on the user's geo-location, Eatr finds and serves up individual restaurants that can be swiped left or right depending on preference. I was project manager, and responsible for front-end rendering and retrieving restaurant information using a Google API.

Check out https://github.com/Eatr/eatr and https://eatr.herokuapp.com/

Flipper — A gendered language converter.

Flips all gendered language in text or a twitter feed. This was a personal project in which I experimented with APIs, MVC, and different parts-of-speech libraries.

Check out https://github.com/lau-ren/flipper-cs and http://lang-per-cs and https://lang-per-cs and <a href="https://lang-per-cs" flipper.herokuapp.com/

I have a proven ability to learn difficult concepts quickly.

I am highly

where

learning is

ongoing.

motivated in

environments

KEY SKILLS

Problem Solver

I enjoy the excitement of coming up with creative solutions for complex problems.

Quick Learner

I have a proven ability to learn difficult concepts quickly and am motivated in environments where learning is ongoing.

Good Collaborator

My interpersonal skills and ability to work in a team are core qualities.

Strong Communicator

I have excellent oral and written communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Litmus, Wellington December 2014 -present

I help prepare qualitative research materials for publication this has involved:

- Literature reviews, database searches
- Audio transcription
- Handling confidential and sensitive data
 Data analysis
- Supporting senior research analysts
- · Working to strict deadlines

Focus Group Host

INK, Wellington

December 2014-present

A client facing role in which I ensure focus groups run smoothly. This involved resolving technical issues and fulfilling special requirements of the clients, i.e. note-taking or catering.

Research Assistant

Human Behaviour Laboratory, Victoria University of Wellington July 2014 - April 2016

My primary role was to assist in the preparation of quantitative research materials for journal publication, this included:

- statistical analysis of datasets, data collection and entry
- oral presentation of research
- keeping accurate records of experiments
- · safeguarding the confidentiality of participants

School of Psychology, Victoria University of Wellington March 2015 - April 2016

I tutored a first year (Introduction to Psychology 2) and third year (Behaviour Analysis) paper. These both involved communicating complex ideas and leading students in class-room discussions.

Interviewer

Applied Developmental Laboratory, Victoria University of Wellington September 2015 - November 2015

I conducted interviews with children in years 3 and 4, following a strict interview guide. This role required clear communication with the school and teachers to minimize classroom disruption

INTERESTS

- Experimenting and building useless programs
- Playing with clay, pottery and ceramics
- Squash, indoor netball, yoga
- · All things tech!

REFERENCES

Available on request.

interpersonal skills and ability to work in a team are core qualities.